<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on Colin Szechy</title>
    <link>http://szechy.me/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on Colin Szechy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 15:38:31 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://szechy.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>transition goals followup</title>
      <link>http://szechy.me/blog/transition-goals-followup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 15:38:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://szechy.me/blog/transition-goals-followup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;transitiongoals-followup&#34;&gt;#transitiongoals followup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some general thoughts: it&amp;rsquo;s been fascinating/fun/interesting to see how my priorities changed as I arrived in California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-growth-things&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Personal growth&amp;rdquo; things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meet-five-5-people-in-a-one-on-one-setting&#34;&gt;Meet five (5) people in a one-on-one setting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting people socially did happen, but not in this fashion. This goal came out of two things: not having substantial friendships after my previous summer internships happened, and a desire to branch out and get to meet new people by confidently inviting them out to places. The first did happen, in a different fashion: I met other interns my age with whom I think I will have lasting friendships. Having an extended co-op (May through December), plus having the ability to go out on long road trips to amazing places in California (like the Marin Headlands and Mammoth Lakes) heavily contributed to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I still want to start/get a lot better/practice meeting people and having lunch one-on-one. I can think of a couple of candidates in the Bay Area I can start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visit-five-5-iconic-places-in-nature&#34;&gt;Visit five (5) iconic places in nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one I accomplished. The final list of twelve, after eight months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marin Headlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Castle Rock State Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mission Peak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half Moon Bay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big Sur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lake Tahoe (twice - once in summer, once for winter skiing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mammoth Lakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mojave Desert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Death Valley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Canyon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zion National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have a lot that I want to tackle, however - being in California has only made my list of places longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinnacles National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequoia National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua Tree National Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salton Sea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mt. Shasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rest of the Sierras (likely some sort of CA-395 highway drive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;take-an-amazing-photo-every-week&#34;&gt;Take an amazing photo every week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the photos that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken from this co-op, I likely got very close to this, despite only using my iPhone (didn&amp;rsquo;t even bring my dSLR). Especially near the end of this co-op, I was essentially there - my Thanksgiving trip had multiple amazing photos each morning and afternoon. You can see my Instagram for proof. Earlier on, however, I did not have as many amazing/adventurous weekends, which ended up being my primary opportunities for amazing photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: I got close to this goal through finding amazing settings for photographs. I should take the weeks in which I don&amp;rsquo;t have these opportunities to try to be more artsy. I&amp;rsquo;m also seriously considering buying myself a Fuji X100T, a great small portable camera that I could throw in my backpack and take anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-24-books&#34;&gt;Read 24 books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got nowhere close with this. I read a total of one and a half books. I first started &lt;em&gt;Between the World and Me&lt;/em&gt; by Ta-Nehisi Coates in June, which I then ended up restarting and finishing on my flights back home in December. In September, I also read &lt;em&gt;Flight Club&lt;/em&gt; by Chuck Palahniuk, which a coworker insisted I borrow from him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goal is something that I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to perceive as even more desirable. A lot of people I&amp;rsquo;ve started admiring for their thoughts are clearly well-read, and not just in Internet thinkpieces. I&amp;rsquo;m just not sure how to gain time to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;document-what-i-created-and-consumed-for-every-day&#34;&gt;Document what I created and consumed for every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I (with about 80-90% accuracy) have tracked my podcast diet over my time in California. I didn&amp;rsquo;t track the TV or Internet that I consumed as well, largely due to little TV consumption and an incredible amount of Internet consumption. I could/should start TV consumption tracking. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to track Internet consumption. I downloaded RescueTime a couple of weeks ago, which feels rather intrusive but could have useful results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to make a post about my podcast diet and the podcasts that I recommend soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;become-physically-fit&#34;&gt;Become physically fit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gained 5-10 pounds since I left Michigan. Being in an office and buying a car means I&amp;rsquo;ve been decently sedentary during the week, despite going out and hiking on weekends. Buying an Apple Watch helped me track and understand my sedentary-ness, and I have put time in my schedule during next semester for working out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-activity-every-day&#34;&gt;Physical activity every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. I went to the gym only a couple of times, although I tried to get out and hike every weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gym-three-times-a-week&#34;&gt;Gym three times a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went about three times in eight months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;run-a-5k-without-stopping&#34;&gt;Run a 5k without stopping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did go for a few runs during August, but never into a good routine (or beyond 2.25 miles). I think if I set a specific 5k as my goal and set a training schedule, I could hold myself to it. This seems like a good goal for after I graduate, and have a consistent life schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-technical-things&#34;&gt;Do technical things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;apply-for-grad-school&#34;&gt;Apply for grad school&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a draft statement of purpose and talked to two professors about recommendation letters, but this ultimately didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I could put forward a competitive application for the high-caliber Ph.D. and master&amp;rsquo;s programs I was looking for. I also received a full-time offer in the Bay Area, that I decided to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;return-offer&#34;&gt;Return offer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received a return offer, and accepted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;volunteer-with-chezy-champs&#34;&gt;Volunteer with Chezy Champs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goal was intended to be a small step towards a larger goal. Rejoining the FIRST Robotics community seemed like a good, constructive use of my time outside of work. Attending Chezy Champs felt like a good first step to rejoining the community, and finding a good role within it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, two things have conspired against this goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I don&amp;rsquo;t think rejoining the FIRST Robotics community is the best use of my time outside of work. I think I need to focus on fulfilling a lot of the goals that I missed (physical activity and exercise, reading books), exploring California, and trying to do constructive things in new areas and fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, Chezy Champs was the same weekend as I was able to attend the Southern California taping of the Grand Tour as a member of the audience, one of my favorite TV shows for years. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedrive.com/a-list/5329/exclusive-inside-the-grand-tour-taping-in-california&#34;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; talks about the taping the day before for the new opening segment - I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend that, but the next day when they taped the in-tent segments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-things&#34;&gt;Fun things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;beat-a-pokemon-game&#34;&gt;Beat a Pokemon game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the previously mentioned old DS Lite and Pokemon Platinum, I beat Spear Pillar sometime in August-ish. So now I just have to defeat the Elite Four. I should have more time at school to finish this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-ridiculous-selfie-with-a-silicon-valley-icon&#34;&gt;Get a ridiculous selfie with a Silicon Valley icon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goal was in the vein of &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in the Bay Area, let&amp;rsquo;s do some silly/stupid Silicon Valley things&amp;rdquo;. I did plenty other things in this vein (chasing Snap Spectacles to Big Sur, feeling like I was in a ridiculously tech-oriented area) that I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any need for this one specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-ride-around-an-amazing-racetrack&#34;&gt;Get a ride around an amazing racetrack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was within grasp for a lot of my co-op, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about it seriously much until the end. I bought a bone-stock BMW E30, which would be a great candidate for a track day (as long as it survived and I could drive it home), but I never got it to one. I did network/make friends with people who go to track days at Laguna Seca, Thunderhill, and Sonoma, so this can definitely still happen in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-to-a-sf-cars-and-coffee-and-or-pebble-beach-concours-d-elegance&#34;&gt;Go to a SF Cars and Coffee and/or Pebble Beach Concours d&amp;rsquo;Elegance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither of these happened, for two different reasons. SF Cars and Coffee has been cancelled for most of the last eight months, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get away during the week of Pebble Beach for the hour-and-a-half (one way) drive. Almost all of the cheap activites are during the week. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized these events are less important; I didn&amp;rsquo;t have trouble meeting people who enjoyed cars. The Bay Area is teeming with them, including the person who I sold my E30 to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solve-a-rubik-s-cube&#34;&gt;Solve a Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completely forgot about this one. It&amp;rsquo;s honestly not that important - something to try when I have free time and I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a puzzle like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;become-ok-at-skateboarding&#34;&gt;Become OK at skateboarding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was contingent on buying a helmet, which I never got around to. I did skate around for about half an hour with one not-great fall, in total. It was difficult finding places to skateboard where it&amp;rsquo;s socially acceptable to skateboard and feels like an open/welcoming space to newcomers. Also, it feels impossible to take good falls like it is for skiing or snowboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-that-i-m-not-sure-how-to-tackle&#34;&gt;Goals that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to tackle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-chewing-my-nails&#34;&gt;Stop chewing my nails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn&amp;rsquo;t happen, either. I didn&amp;rsquo;t put much thought to it besides further recognizing the need to do so. I think I might try fidget tools and painting my nails next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-a-better-sense-of-style-and-wardrobe&#34;&gt;Have a better sense of style and wardrobe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I made progress on this front. My work attire started as a button-up with jeans or chinos, and gradually became hoodies with a more colorful set of V-necks and jeans or chinos. I also tried bleaching and then dying my hair, which I thought worked well and I should play around with more. I was definitely more conscientous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to work on removing hoodies largely from my wardrobe - that really sticks out as being lazy, male, and tech. I also want to explore/mess around more with my hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-cooking&#34;&gt;Start cooking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn&amp;rsquo;t happen - there was cheap food for lunch and dinner that was far too accessible. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this&amp;rsquo;ll happen when I&amp;rsquo;m full-time either: I have too many things I want to do with my time, and far too many cool and interesting places to eat in the Bay Area in my free time. I should really prioritize this&amp;hellip; ugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;help-ship-an-ios-app&#34;&gt;Help ship an iOS app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up not working on non-work projects during my co-op. I would still like to do this, but I feel similarly to my involvement in FIRST Robotics and Chezy Champs: it&amp;rsquo;s simply not as interesting to me anymore, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather try other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;own-a-console-play-more-video-games&#34;&gt;Own a console/play more video games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought an Xbox One in September that I sold right before I finished my co-op. I rarely played it, despite having my two favorite games (Forza Motorsports 6 and Forza Horizon 2). I did end up playing some PC games (namely Team Fortress 2 - which essentially is like comfort food to me - and some Counter Strike: Global Offensive). I could see myself maybe playing more PC games (and building a desktop) to have a social thing to do with friends farther away. Console games have less appeal to me, other then for exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;write-more&#34;&gt;Write more&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made some progress on this front. In October, I spent $50 on the macOS and iOS apps for &lt;a href=&#34;http://dayoneapp.com&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; to serve as an impetus to start journaling. I&amp;rsquo;m successfully journaling every couple of days (usually every day, occassionally twice a week). That&amp;rsquo;s served as good writing practice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-thoughts-reflection&#34;&gt;Last thoughts/reflection&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#transitiongoals</title>
      <link>http://szechy.me/blog/transition-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://szechy.me/blog/transition-goals/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As this semester ends, I stand on the precipice of a fake graduation: I’ll be spending eight months working in the real world in the California Bay Area far away from Ann Arbor and the world I currently know. I’ll be in the Bay Area from May through December (if you’re in the area, I would love to see you — please message me via Twitter or Facebook or carrier pigeon!), but more then that: I’ll be far away from all of my friends and family in Michigan and southwest Ontario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this small life transition in the next month precipitating a huge life transition post-graduation, I’ve started feeling… a bit lost. Growing up through the modern American school system means having academic goals set reguarly for myself. But the real world isn’t as straightforward, and this transition seemed like an opportunity to come up with some real life goals, based around ideas and thoughts that I’ve had in my head that have been blocked by schoolwork or school-related activities. With a large amount of time to spend outside of work, I want some ideas of how to spend that time well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another goal is to remind my future self of my current mindset and priorities. This is something that I think I struggle with a lot — understanding myself, and how I change over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also tried to structure this list as achievable and/or concrete (oftentimes quantitative) goals. I’ve included some goals at the bottom that are more general, but I wasn’t sure how to make achievable or concrete in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-growth-things&#34;&gt;“Personal growth” things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Personal growth” is in quotes because I really don’t know what I want out of personal growth, or what personal growth really means. However, all of the following were things I wanted to do, that others seem to describe as personal growth — in that they are .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meet-five-5-people-in-a-one-on-one-setting&#34;&gt;Meet five (5) people in a one-on-one setting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I struggle to meet and get to know new people, well, because I’m on the shyer side when it comes to completely new people, not that sociable, and poor at making small talk. I want to meet five new people, one-on-one, over a meal or some other prolonged activity (at least an hour) to meet new people, and simply practice social skills. Ideally, at least some of these are dates, and not all of them are over food but incorporate other activities (like hiking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visit-five-5-iconic-places-in-nature&#34;&gt;Visit five (5) iconic places in nature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a total of four days on the West Coast (or west of Austin, TX) in my life — I want to make the most of visiting and exploring the great Western United States and its nature. I’ve only been camping for a total of three nights, and I don’t have a specific list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bigsur.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leftpic&#34; /&gt; &lt;!--Big Sur--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other then setting a goal, I don’t have a great plan to achieve this one, which is intentional: I want to meet other like-minded people who are also motivated to explore. I’ve been thinking about places like Yosemite, Big Sur, and Mission Peak, as well as Crater Lake, Lake Tahoe, Desert Valley, Sequoia National Park, and Land’s End. The sheer number of iconic opportunities in California, versus Michigan, is dazzling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;take-an-amazing-photo-every-week&#34;&gt;Take an amazing photo every week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had an interest in photography (after buying a dSLR in eighth grade), but haven’t had time to pursue it in college. Without the obligations of school, I should have time to get more use out of my dSLR camera (or maybe buy a new one, since mine is from 2008 and has less megapixels then my iPhone) or take casual, opportune shots with my iPhone. Setting a goal of one high-quality photo worth sharing on my Flickr or with friends is a way to begin trying to do that again. I want to explore more portrait photography, which ties in nicely with some of my other goals that have social elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-24-books&#34;&gt;Read 24 books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stereotypical reading goal is 24 books in a year, or two per month. I want to hold myself to that as well, and I’ve started actively tracking what I’ve read on Goodreads. I‘m starting this week with the historical fiction novel It Can’t Happen Here by Sinclair Lewis, which describes the rise of a populist fascist US President in the mid-1930s (perhaps a bit appropriate to this year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;document-what-i-created-and-consumed-for-every-day&#34;&gt;Document what I created and consumed for every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is inspired by someone else (for whom I can’t find the link), who has documented for multiple years what content they consumed (primarily video, books, and podcasts) for several years, to look at and reflect on later. I attempted to do the same job in January and stopped due to failing to remember between school, coursework, and extracurriculars — so I’d like to renew my focus on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be something I post monthly about on Medium, to keep myself on track (and as recommendations to other people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;become-physically-fit&#34;&gt;Become physically fit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently weigh more today then I have ever weighed in my life before, and not in a good way. This trend needs to change immediately. Even better: I’d like to finally become toned, remove most of my fat, and not be ashamed to see my body in the mirror. Here are my actionables on that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-activity-every-day&#34;&gt;Physical activity every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!--My team in last summer’s intern basketball league, which rekindled a love of basketball and being outside.--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;basketball.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leftpic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently weigh more today then I have ever weighed in my life before, and not in a good way. So, I want to get up and move significantly every day. At the minimum, this means a gym visit or a run of over two miles, or playing frisbee or basketball or skateboarding. Just something physical and active. As a subgoal, I want to play hockey (street or on a rink) at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gym-three-times-a-week&#34;&gt;Gym three times a week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of physical activity every week, I want to have a regular gym routine. I’m not 100% sure what my routine will be (other then that I don’t want to skip leg day) or how it will fit into my schedule yet, but there’ll be a gym at the apartment complex I’ll be living at, and possibly at work. I’m thinking about trying to do this as part of my morning pre-work routine for the first time in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;run-a-5k-without-stopping&#34;&gt;Run a 5k without stopping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to run a 5k without stopping. If I can get into a routine of running, and slowly pushing myself, this should definitely be accomplishable by December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-technical-things&#34;&gt;Do technical things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;apply-for-grad-school&#34;&gt;Apply for grad school&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to seriously apply to computer science doctorate (and maybe masters’) programs in the upcoming year (most applications are due in December). That means, in this order: scouting out possible schools (ideally in CS systems research), trying to make connections with possible research advisors at those schools, studying for and taking the GRE this summer, getting three recommendation letters, applying for a NSF Graduate Fellowship, and making an amazing personal statement (especially with my GPA). Not simple or straightforward, but something I want to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if I want to go to grad school, but it has a lot of appeal to me, and I’d like to keep the option open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;return-offer&#34;&gt;Return offer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty clear-cut: I want to perform extremely well during my internship/co-op-, so I can have the ability to return after I get my undergraduate degree, regardless of what I want to do next with my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;volunteer-with-chezy-champs&#34;&gt;Volunteer with Chezy Champs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!--Chezy Champs 2014. (Photo credit: Team 254)--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;chezychamps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rightpic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t given back to the high school robotics community (specifically the FIRST Robotics Competition) since high school graduation and leaving Team 2337, the EngiNERDs, due to college. I’d like to check out the California FRC scene to see if it’d be something I’m interested in, and volunteering at the premier offseason in the area, Chezy Champs, seems like a great way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-things&#34;&gt;Fun things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;beat-a-pokemon-game&#34;&gt;Beat a Pokemon game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never owned a Nintendo handheld console, until I walked into an Ann Arbor gaming store in August and bought an old DS Lite and Pokemon Platinum. I think I’m missing out on an important part of everyone’s childhood if I don’t beat the Elite Four. I’m currently stuck at Spear Pillar, after nine months of having owned the game with school and other activities in the way, so hopefully I can pick it back up in California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;selfie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rightpic&#34; /&gt;
&lt;!--A normal, boring selfie with Tim Cook. What if he had a massive grin on his face, like my normal selfies with people?--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-ridiculous-selfie-with-a-silicon-valley-icon&#34;&gt;Get a ridiculous selfie with a Silicon Valley icon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m going to be in the Valley for eight months, attending various intern and different companies’ events, I desperately want a ridiculous selfie with Larry Page, Tim Cook, Sheryl Sandberg, Jony Ive, or someone of that status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-a-ride-around-an-amazing-racetrack&#34;&gt;Get a ride around an amazing racetrack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California is full of amazing, iconic racetracks like Laguna Seca, Thunderhill, Sonoma/Infineon, and Willow Springs. I want to get out to at least one, and get a ride around it (driving, or as a passenger), hopefully with friends. That likely means going to a track day, and striking up conversations with fellow automotive enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;go-to-a-sf-cars-and-coffee-and-or-pebble-beach-concours-d-elegance&#34;&gt;Go to a SF Cars and Coffee and/or Pebble Beach Concours d’Elegance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the previous item, the main goal here is to actually invigorate my love of cars by finding people who are also into cars, and going to awesome events with them. SF Cars and Coffee is a small impromptu car show/discussion on the first Saturday of every month on Treasure Island, and Pebble Beach’s Concours d’Elegance, an insanely amazing car show of iconic prewar and postwar cars, is from August 16–21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solve-a-rubik-s-cube&#34;&gt;Solve a Rubik’s Cube&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my friends Mayank, Pavi, and Connor picked up solving Rubik’s cubes this semester, I was reminded that I’ve always wanted to learn to solve one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;become-ok-at-skateboarding&#34;&gt;Become OK at skateboarding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a skateboard for Christmas, and I’m going to be in California. Hopefully it’ll be a useful way to commute to work, and I can become comfortable that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-that-i-m-not-sure-how-to-tackle&#34;&gt;Goals that I’m not sure how to tackle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of these goals, I’m just not sure how to tackle them in a quantitative or achievable way. But I want to be thinking about them, and possibly come up with milestones as my time in California goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-chewing-my-nails&#34;&gt;Stop chewing my nails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My nails have not really grown in — I’ve left them bitten to the quick for years, and it needs to end. I’m just not sure how to constructively try to work on this, other then just cold turkey forever (definitely an option, but I’ve tried it before and failed). If you have any advice, please send me a message!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-a-better-sense-of-style-and-wardrobe&#34;&gt;Have a better sense of style and wardrobe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had numerous people, for years, tell me that my daily outfits are boring and very similar to other people. I have also rarely received compliments on my haircuts, especially not when I rocked the Bieber bowl cut. I want to reverse this trend by being more conscientious about what I wear, and finding a haircut that myself and others enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-cooking&#34;&gt;Start cooking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last summer living in Austin, removed from Michigan and my family, I began to conservatively cook for myself. I’d like to become even better and take this to the next level, although I’m not sure how to do so yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;help-ship-an-ios-app&#34;&gt;Help ship an iOS app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a couple of ideas, primarily related to the FIRST Robotics Competition, and I might try to see where I can get with them before and after my work term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;own-a-console-play-more-video-games&#34;&gt;Own a console/play more video games (?)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve essentially stopped playing video games since I went to college. I’ve never fully determined if not playing video games was a good or a bad thing, but it’s something I think about. I think I enjoy social video games the most — whether playing Team Fortress 2 with friends online, or Super Smash Bros. or Forza in person — but a lot of video games are solitary activities that waste time, and don’t necessarily contribute a lot to building interesting, healthy people. There are many video games that have various benefits, and having something mindless for downtime is always good — but spending hundreds of dollars on that… I haven’t made up my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;write-more&#34;&gt;Write more&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documenting these goals seems like a good first step! So does writing about the monthly content I’m consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;last-thoughts&#34;&gt;Last thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t anticipate on achieving all of these goals that are not the physical fitness ones. A lot of these goals are very normal/“stereotypical”, but I don’t think that’s a bad thing. Trying new things to learn more about one’s self, physical fitness, and having fun are all important things that nearly all humans seek and enjoy. Having some sort of idea of how to achieve that — by, say, making a list of possible ideas that have been spun around in one’s mind a lot — is helpful and useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll miss everyone in Michigan and southwest Ontario, and look forward to seeing you around the next MHacks in the fall, Thanksgiving, and after December!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt;I want to give a big thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@stestefanfan/done-ba4319ec440d#.f8oinrik7&#34;&gt;Stefan Aleksic’s //DONE article&lt;/a&gt; for inspiring this goal creation process, and some of the goals themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I lost my fitness band and now I don’t know what to do</title>
      <link>http://szechy.me/blog/fitness-band/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://szechy.me/blog/fitness-band/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, so I don’t feel that desperate, I promise. I’ve only felt anxious and nervous and wrong a couple of times today. And a couple more times yesterday. OK? And each of the six days before that, which is perfectly fine. Right? Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I just need to get this situation off my chest, and I won’t feel this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for Christmas six months ago, I decided to get a fitness wearable. I’m not pleased with the shape my body is in as my body fat percentage is really where I don’t want it to be, and at school I don’t sleep as much as I should, and I never had time to work out. So, I thought that getting data on my sleep and physical activity would be useful. I also liked the idea of having a smart alarm to wake me up at the “optimum” point in my sleep cycle. Looking over reviews online, I decided to get a Jawbone UP24, because it actually looked good, and tracked the basics at a good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having to get a replacement because the original band didn’t work, I gave the UP24 a shot at working in my life. Immediately, I had constant feedback on what I was doing, at all times. Every morning, I had new data to pour over on my sleep and sleep cycles. Every evening, the results of a new game to beat my steps goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;withband.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leftpic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture of myself and the companion, out for the day with matching flowers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was like my Twitter feed: my UP app became a hub of new information that was different every hour — the perfect complement to the other content I was checking obsessively. Unlike the sick Taylor Swift BuzzFeed quiz on whether Eddy Cue or Calvin Harris is right for her, or my new group message notifications from my friend group back in Michigan and the group in Texas and the Facebook notifications from Hackathon Hackers and -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, right. So, my UP app was different. The app was about meeting my goals, keeping track of where I am physically, and staying on track for becoming healthier and being fit. I absolutely loved beating my step count, being under on my calorie count for the day (food was something I just started logging in the last month), and seeing my sleep quality statistics. My band was more then on my wrist: it felt more like a never-resting companion that would never leave, supporting me on my way to the better health I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This love wasn’t perfect. My UP24 wasn’t waterproof, so it didn’t accompany me to the shower. The band’s orange skin also got dirty quickly, and in the last week became loose and could be shifted to completely overlap the button at one end. But no love is, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months in a statement is an interesting time. It’s right after one of the two make-or-break points, I think, which is: is this relationship going to be long or short-term? Around three or four months, there’s been enough time for the two sides to become familiar with one another’s foibles, flaws, and favorites — emotionally, mentally, even physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was six months in when the band left me. I took it off to play sweaty sand volleyball. I set it in my shoes… and came back an hour later to find it lying on the dirty ground. No problem, I’ll just briefly wash it off when I get home, I said as I put it somewhere and -
that was the last time I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No big deal,&lt;/em&gt; I thought. &lt;em&gt;I don’t need my fitness band, and it’s not as expensive as my iPhone or Mac — man, both of which I’d be up a creek without.&lt;/em&gt; Suddenly, I had this hole I could fill with another gadget. &lt;em&gt;Hey, this means I have an excuse to get an Apple Watch. Or I could buy another band. Or I could be responsible this summer and save that $100+ for university. Or I could simply relax without one. I lived without the band once, I can do it again for a while. It’s not essential to my life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly put the matter of losing the band out of my mind for the rest of the day, distracted by volleyball and basketball and friends, and I hadn’t thought about it until I went to bed that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first became acquainted with my band, my arms felt awkward — visually lopsided by the vibrant orange wristband. Over the first three months of wearing the band, the difference in appearance gradually became a new normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was putting on pajamas, suddenly it hit me: how disorienting it was not to visibly see the band against my arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laid in bed, and immediately reached to press the button to put the tracker in sleep mode — no, it wasn’t there. I immediately felt disorientated. It honestly felt like a key part of me was missing. I didn’t get why I felt this way then about a simple band, but that’s how I felt. And still do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;band.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rightpic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally woke up in the morning, turned off my alarm, and reached to press the button — no, it still wasn’t there. I felt confusion… and fear. Fear that this morning’s sleep wouldn’t be tracked, and there was now officially a hole in my data. My weekly average was messed up, my spot in the top 20% of UPers for steps in jeop— no, stop. Colin. Shake it off, just like Tay would do. It’s just a piece of plastic, fiberglass and silicon. This band is not like I had lost a relationship with someone, just something. It wasn’t, it couldn’t, it shouldn’t be as important. Right?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of routine, this all went on while I got ready for a morning shower. I simultaneously tried to grab the band and take it off without look — no! Why did I keep on going for it? How did walking into the bathroom cause a Pavlovian response to play with the band?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my shower, trying to refocus for work that day. I got out, dried myself off, brushed my teeth, and put on deodorant. Out of pure habit, before leaving, I looked frantically around my bathroom for a neon orange circle. I was used to having to search for things for a long time, and being flummoxed by temporarily losing important things before finding them in the last time I had seen them. But this time, I had no such last place. The band was gone. It was truly gone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>